宜宾市二零二零年初中学业水平考试暨高中阶段学校招生考试英语听力部分，做题时先将答案标在试卷上。录音内容结束后，你将有两分钟的时间将试卷上的答案转涂到答题卡上。第一节：听下面五段对话，每段对话后有一个小题，从题中所给的三个选项中选出最佳选项。听完每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一小题。每段对话读两遍：听第一段对话，回答第一题
Sarah, how long have you lived in Yibin?
I've lived here since I was three years old.
Now I'm eighteen years old.
Sarah, how long have you lived in Yibin?
I've lived here since I was three years old.
Now I'm eighteen years old.
听第二段对话，回答第二题。
How about my fish?
It couldn't be better.
You are really a good cook.
How about my fish?
It couldn't be better.
You are really a cook.
听第三段对话，回答第三题。
What do you think of Lihua?
Well, he always helps us whenever we are in trouble.
听第四段对话，回答第四题。
My brother likes basketball and football.
Really? I don't like either of those sports, but I do like table tennis.
I don't like either of those sports, but I do like table tennis.
听第五段对话，回答第五题。
Aren't you going to see the film?
They say that it's wonderful.
I'm afraid I can't, because I don't feel very well today.
Aren't you going to see the film?
They say that it's wonderful.
I'm afraid I can't, because I don't feel very well today.
第二节：听下面几段对话或独白。每段对话或独白后有几个小题，从题中所给的
,B I plan to stay in the city for two weeks, but I have to make it just ten days.
三个选项。中选出最佳选项。听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。每段对话或独白读两遍。听第六段对话，回答第。小题。
Why? There will be an important meeting next weekend.
You're really busy.
Anyway, how about having supper together tonight?
I'd love to, but I'm seeing some friends this evening.
What about tomorrow?
Okay, see you tomorrow.
See you. how long will you stay in the city?
I plan to stay in the city for two weeks, but I have to make it just ten days.
Why? There will be an important meeting next weekend.
You're really busy.
Anyway, how about having supper together tonight?
I'd love to, but I'm seeing some friends this evening.
What about tomorrow?
Okay, see you tomorrow.
See you. How is your mother feeling these days?
听第七段对话，回答第八至十三个小题。
Much better. She should be back home in a few days.
The operation was successful, and the doctors say she will get well soon.
That's wonderful. When will you be back on your job?
I think I need a week to take care of her and do some cleaning for her coming home.
Why don't you ask someone to do it?
I'm really worried about my mother.
She is seventy -five years old.
It's really kind of you.
How is your mother feeling these days?
Much better. She should be back home in a few days.
The operation was successful, and the doctors say she will get well soon.
That's wonderful. When will you be back on your job?
I think I need a week to take care of her and do some cleaning for her coming home.
Why don't you ask someone to do it?
I'm really worried about my mother.
She is seventy -five years old.
It's really kind of you.
听第八段对话，回答第十一至十三三个小题。
Hello, the City Sports Center.
Helen speaking. Hello, I'm Tom.
I'd like some information, please.
Are you open at the weekend?
Yes, all days including Saturday and Sunday, but we are closed on Monday.
can I swim in the afternoon?
Between three and five o 'clock.
A school uses the pool from one until three.
And then, at five, there is the beginners class.
Okay, I'd like to play tennis too.
Is that possible?
Yes, we also have basketball and football.
And after you swim,
you should try the cafe upstairs.
It's near the changing rooms.
Hello, the City Sports Center.
Helen speaking. Hello, I'm Tom.
I'd like some information, please.
Are you open at weekend?
Yes, all days including Saturday and Sunday, but we are closed on Monday.
can I swim in the afternoon?
Between three and five o 'clock.
A school uses the pool from one until three.
And then, at five, there is the beginners class.
Okay, I'd like to play tennis too.
Is that possible?
Yes, we also have basketball and football.
And after you swim, you should try the cafe upstairs.
It's near the changing rooms.
听第九段对话，回答第十四至十六三个小题。
So, how are things going, Well,
to tell you the truth, Carla, I was feeling quite good last Sunday, but I started to
feel rather bad on Monday morning.
Oh, what's the problem?
Well, I had a pretty bad fever.
I went to the doctor and he gave me some medicine to stop the fever, but it didn't
seem to help.
You know, I have some traditional Chinese medicine.
It's a kind of tea.
You just drink it four times a day.
Does it really work?
Of course, it works.
Okay, I'll try your magic tea.
So, how are things going, Stephen?
Well, to tell you the truth, Carla, I was feeling quite good last Sunday, but I
started to feel rather bad on Monday morning.
Oh, what's the problem?
Well, I had a pretty bad fever.
I went to the doctor and he gave me some medicine to stop the fever, but it didn't
seem to help.
You know, I have some traditional Chinese medicine.
It's a kind of tea.
You just drink it four times a day.
Does it really work?
Of course, it works.
Okay, I'll try your magic tea.
听下面一段独白，回答第十七至二十四个小题。
Boys and girls, I have some good news to tell you.
The Rayborn Training Center is organizing an event on June 14th, starting at 9 in
the morning and ending at 8.30 in the evening.
It will be held in the Long Stadium.
You can get there by bus 202 or 305.
This event will include a number of fun activities,
with a variety of games such as hide and seek.
There will also be all kinds of great food to enjoy.
This event will not only have games and food,
but will also give you a chance to hear the beautiful voices of two famous singers.
Tickets will be sold at every underground station starting on July 11th.
The money raised from ticket sales will be given to poor homeless children.
Don't miss this chance to have fun and help the poor at the same time.
Boys and girls, I have some good news to tell you.
The Rayborn Training Center is organizing an event on June 14th, starting at 9 in
the morning and ending at 8.30 in the evening.
It will be held in the Long Stadium.
can get there by bus 202 or 305.
This event will include a number of fun activities,
with a variety of games such as hide and seek.
There will also be all kinds of great food to enjoy.
This event will not only have games and food,
but will also give you a chance to hear the beautiful voices of two famous singers.
Tickets will be sold at every underground station starting on July 11th.
The money raised from ticket sales will be given to poor homeless children.
Don't miss this chance to have fun and help the poor at the same time.
现在你有两分钟的时间，将试卷上的答案转涂到答题卡上。
The money from children.
The money sales children.
Thank you for watching.
Thank you. The
听力考试到此结束。